

# PROFILE

Big Data Specialist at IBM with total experience of 3.3 years in Big Data.

#### **AWARDS**

Awarded Excellence award for exceptional performance in Big Data Development from IBM.

Won ZONAL ROUND from INSTITUTE OF USA in Robotics and MATLAB for Hand gesture recognition.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified JAVA Programmer awarded

by HP with grade A
Certification from Udemy on
Python, Hive, Pyspark, Scala,
ML using Python and Spark.

Acclaim Badge holder for Certified SPARK and SPARK ML developer.

Hacker-rank certification in Python.

#### MIHIR SINGH

# PYSPARK 2+, HADOOP AND ML DEVELOPER

The best of work comes to those who earn it.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

IBM- BIG DATA and ML engineer Apr,2020-Present
Accenture -Big Data and ML Engineer Feb,2018—Apr,2020

#### **PROJECTS**

- Data Warehousing and Aggregation: Worked on end to end data ingestion techniques from various source using SPARK JDBC and in various SCD types (Type 1 and 2). Have worked on complex problem and delivered solutions with optimized results in spark sql and Structured Streaming.
- Big Data Developer Data migration and Ingestion in Hadoop
  Developed Data Ingestion techniques in Pyspark to extract and
  transform using Spark, calculate KPI's and pushing the data to
  Hive table. The process was automated using Oozie workflow
  and Scheduled via a coordinator. The infrastructure used from
  the project was Azure HDInsight (Cloud services).
- Suggested order model development using SparkMI:
  Have developed model in SparkMI using inbuilt K-means
  clustering and Apiori Algorithm(custom algo to promote
  products in particular category) for a recommender system that
  used unsupervised learning to classify and recommend
  focused products based on previous purchase.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Amity University B. Tech CS&E:** 2013 – 2017 CGPA: 6.53 Grade A **ISC:** 2012 – 2013 79% Computer Science and Mathematics

ICSE: 2010-2011 80.59% All subjects

# **SKILLS**

Spark 2.4.5		100%
Python 3.5	550/	90%
ML&SparkM	65%	
L		100%
Hadoop	70%	100%
Hive		
Azure HdInsight		

0.00% 25.00% 50.00% 75.00% 100.00%